Feel the need... The need for speed.
Top Gun: Maverick is a action, drama film directed by Joseph Kosinski.
After more than thirty years of service as one of the Navy’s top aviators, and dodging the advancement in rank that would ground him, Pete “Maverick”
Mitchell finds himself training a detachment of TOP GUN graduates for a specialized mission the likes of which no living pilot has ever seen.
Capt. Pete 'Maverick' Mitchell, played by Tom Cruise.
Adm. Tom 'Iceman' Kazansky, played by Val Kilmer.
Lt. Bradley 'Rooster' Bradshaw, played by Miles Teller.
Penny Benjamin, played by Jennifer Connelly.
Wo-1. Bernie 'Hondo' Coleman, played by Bashir Salahuddin.
Adm. Beau 'Cyclone' Simpson, played by Jon Hamm.
Top Gun: Maverick is a 2022 American action drama film directed by Joseph Kosinski and written by Ehren Kruger,
Eric Warren Singer, and Christopher McQuarrie, from a story by Peter Craig and Justin Marks.
In this sequel to the 1986 film Top Gun, Tom Cruise reprises his
starring role as the naval aviator Pete "Maverick" Mitchell.
The ensemble cast also features Miles Teller, Jennifer Connelly, Jon Hamm, Glen Powell, Monica
Barbaro, Lewis Pullman, Ed Harris, and Val Kilmer (in his final film role).
The story involves Maverick confronting his past while training a group of younger Top Gun
graduates, including the son of his deceased best friend, for a dangerous mission.
Development of a Top Gun sequel was announced in 2010 by Paramount Pictures.
Cruise, along with co-producer Jerry Bruckheimer and
director Tony Scott, were asked to return.
Craig wrote a draft of the screenplay in 2012, but the
project stalled when Scott died later that year.
Top Gun: Maverick was later dedicated to Scott's memory.
Production resumed in 2017, after Kosinski was hired to direct.
Principal photography, which involved the use of IMAX-certified 6K full-frame cameras, took
place from May 2018 to April 2019 in California, Washington, and Maryland.
The film's complex action sequences—and later the COVID-19 pandemic—delayed
its release, which was initially scheduled for July 12, 2019.
During the pandemic, several streaming companies attempted to purchase the streaming rights to the film from Paramount, but all
offers were declined on the orders of Cruise, who insisted that it should be released exclusively in theaters.
Top Gun: Maverick premiered at CinemaCon on April 28, 2022, and was theatrically
released in the United States on May 27 by Paramount Pictures.
The film was widely praised by critics, with many
deeming it superior to its predecessor.
It was named one of the top ten films of 2022 by the National Board of Review and by the American Film Institute and
nominated for six awards at the 95th Academy Awards (including Best Picture), winning Best Sound.
Top Gun: Maverick grossed $1.496 billion worldwide, making it the
second-highest-grossing film of 2022 and the highest-grossing film of Cruise's career.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of fighter pilot, u.s. navy,
sequel, nuclear weapons, military.
The tone is emotional.